Procrastination is often seen as the enemy of productivity.
拖延症常被视为生产力的大敌。
Images of lazy people with feet up on desks or wasting time to dodge work spring to mind at the very mention of the word.
一提到这个词，人们脑海里就会浮现出懒人把脚翘在桌上、或是为逃避工作而消磨时间的画面。
And there are many things which indicate that procrastination is a problem which needs addressing.
而且有诸多现象表明，拖延症是一个亟待解决的问题。
But could there be some benefits to it too?
但它难道就没有任何益处吗？
We live in a high-octane world – always on the go, racing from one task to another.
我们生活在一个快节奏的世界里，总是行色匆匆，忙完一项任务紧跟着就开始下一项任务。
And at times, duties, be it work or personal, can feel relentless – with our nose constantly to the grindstone.
有时候，无论是工作还是私人事务，这些职责都显得永无止境，让我们不得不埋头苦干。
Sometimes we just need to switch off, chill out and reboot.
有时候，我们就是需要彻底放松、舒缓身心、重新调整状态。
A little procrastination can help detach us from the pressures of modern life.
适度的拖延，能帮我们暂时摆脱现代生活的压力。
According to psychotherapist F Diane Barth, watching TV, taking a long bath or listening to music can help us to ease off.
心理治疗师F·黛安·巴特表示，看电视、泡个热水澡或是听听音乐，都能帮助我们放松下来。
And it’s possible that procrastination has become more prevalent during the pandemic.
在疫情期间，拖延症的现象可能变得更为普遍。
With many countries going through lockdowns, some of us have suddenly found ourselves with more time – not having the hours of commutes, or options of social activities we once took for granted.
随着许多国家实施封锁政策，我们中的一些人突然拥有了更多空闲时间——那些曾经习以为常的通勤时间没了，各类社交活动的选择也消失了。
Being at home, many of us quickly discovered that it is impossible to be productive 24-7.
居家生活让很多人很快意识到，想要一天24小时、一周7天时刻保持高效是不可能的。
That extra relaxation can help us to be more productive or creative in the long run, allowing us to clear our minds and focus better.
从长远来看，这些额外的放松时间能让我们更具效率和创造力，帮助我们理清思绪、更好地集中注意力。
The issue is that many of us see that time not working as lost time.
问题在于，我们很多人都把不工作的时间看作是虚度光阴。
And we almost develop a sense of guilt related to not making the most of every moment.
而且我们还会因为没能充分利用每一刻而产生愧疚感。
German sociologist and economist Max Weber says that we’ve almost got to the point of believing that the busier we are, the better, and that there is a sense of morality connected with time usage.
德国社会学家兼经济学家马克斯·韦伯表示，我们几乎已经陷入了一种认知误区，认为越忙碌越好，并且将时间的利用方式和道德感挂钩。
It seems important to remember that taking a little time away from yourself is not just slacking off.
但我们必须记住，给自己留一点放松的时间，绝不仅仅是偷懒。
So, while being productive is important, it seems that some amount of downtime and procrastination can help us to relax and become more focussed.
因此，尽管保持高效很重要，但适度的休息和拖延，似乎能帮助我们放松身心、提升专注力。
The next time you feel really stressed, why not try wasting a little time? You might just like it.
下次当你感到压力山大时，不妨试着“浪费”一点时间，说不定你会喜欢这种感觉。